<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Apache Paimon</title>
    <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Apache Paimon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/overview/</guid>
      <description>Overview #  Apache Paimon(incubating) is a streaming data lake platform that supports high-speed data ingestion, change data tracking and efficient real-time analytics.
Architecture #  As shown in the architecture above:
Read/Write: Paimon supports a versatile way to read/write data and perform OLAP queries.
 For reads, it supports consuming data  from historical snapshots (in batch mode), from the latest offset (in streaming mode), or reading incremental snapshots in a hybrid way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Concepts</title>
      <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/basic-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/basic-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Basic Concepts #  Snapshot #  A snapshot captures the state of a table at some point in time. Users can access the latest data of a table through the latest snapshot. By time traveling, users can also access the previous state of a table through an earlier snapshot.
Partition #  Paimon adopts the same partitioning concept as Apache Hive to separate data.
Partitioning is an optional way of dividing a table into related parts based on the values of particular columns like date, city, and department.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Layouts</title>
      <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/file-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/file-layouts/</guid>
      <description>File Layouts #  All files of a table are stored under one base directory. Paimon files are organized in a layered style. The following image illustrates the file layout. Starting from a snapshot file, Paimon readers can recursively access all records from the table.
Snapshot Files #  All snapshot files are stored in the snapshot directory.
A snapshot file is a JSON file containing information about this snapshot, including</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
