<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Append Table on Apache Paimon</title>
    <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Append Table on Apache Paimon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/overview/</guid>
      <description>Overview #  If a table does not have a primary key defined, it is an append table by default.
You can only insert a complete record into the table in streaming. This type of table is suitable for use cases that do not require streaming updates (such as log data synchronization).
We highly recommend using Append Scalable Table. (bucket = -1).  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Append Scalable Table</title>
      <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/append-scalable-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/append-scalable-table/</guid>
      <description>Append Scalable Table #  Definition #  By defining &#39;bucket&#39; = &#39;-1&#39; in table properties, you can assign a special mode (we call it &amp;ldquo;unaware-bucket mode&amp;rdquo;) to this table (see Example). In this mode, all the things are different. We don&amp;rsquo;t have the concept of bucket anymore, and we don&amp;rsquo;t guarantee the order of streaming read. We regard this table as a batch off-line table ( although we can stream read and write still).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Append Queue Table</title>
      <link>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/append-queue-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//paimon.apache.org/docs/0.7/concepts/append-table/append-queue-table/</guid>
      <description>Append Queue Table #  Definition #  In this mode, you can regard append table as a queue separated by bucket. Every record in the same bucket is ordered strictly, streaming read will transfer the record to down-stream exactly in the order of writing. To use this mode, you do not need to config special configurations, all the data will go into one bucket as a queue. You can also define the bucket and bucket-key to enable larger parallelism and disperse data (see Example).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
